named William Muir studied chickens.
يدعى ويلليم ميور الدجاج.
He was interested in productivity --
كان مهتما بالانتاجية
I think it's something that concerns all of us --
-انا اعتقد انه شيء يقلقنا جميعا-
but it's easy to measure in chickens because you just count the eggs.
و لكن من السهل قياس الدجاج لأنك فقط تعد البيض.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
He wanted to know what could make his chickens more productive,
كان يريد معرفة ماذا يجعل دجاجه يزيد الإنتاج
so he devised a beautiful experiment.
لذلك ابتكر تجربة جميلة.
Chickens live in groups, so first of all, he selected just an average flock,
الدجاج يعيش في مجموعات، لذلك اولاً، اختار فقط قطيعة متوسطة،
and he let it alone for six generations.
و تركها وحدها لستة اجيال.
But then he created a second group
و لكن بعدها انشأ مجموعة ثانية
of the individually most productive chickens --
مكونة من الدجاج الفردي الأكثر إنتاجية
you could call them superchickens --
يمكنك تسميتهم الدجاج السوبر
and he put them together in a superflock,
و وضعهم معاً في قطيعة سوبر
and each generation, he selected only the most productive for breeding.
و مع كل جيل، إختار فقط الأكثر إنتاجية للتناسل.
After six generations had passed,
بعد مرور ستة اجيال،
what did he find?
ماذا وجد؟
Well, the first group, the average group, was doing just fine.
حسناً، المجموعة الأولى ،المجموعة المتوسطة، كانت بخير.
They were all plump and fully feathered
كانوا جميعهم ممتلئي الجسم و الريش مكتمل
and egg production had increased dramatically.
و زاد انتاج البيض بشكل كبير.
What about the second group?
ماذا عن المجموعة الثانية؟
Well, all but three were dead.
حسناً، كلهم ماعدا ثلاثة ماتوا.
They'd pecked the rest to death.
كانوا يهاجمون البقية حتى الموت.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The individually productive chickens had only achieved their success
الدجاج الفردي الأكثر إنتاجية كان فقط يحقق نجاحه
by suppressing the productivity of the rest.
عن طريق قمع إنتاج البقية.
Now, as I've gone around the world talking about this and telling this story
الآن، بما اني ذهبت حول العالم اتكلم عن هذا الموضوع و هذه القصة
in all sorts of organizations and companies,
في كل انواع المنظمات و الشركات
people have seen the relevance almost instantly,
رأى الناس العلاقة تقريباً في نفس اللحظة
and they come up and they say things to me like,
و جاءوا و قالوا لي اشياء مثل
"That superflock, that's my company."
"هذه المجموعة السوبر، هذه شركتي"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Or, "That's my country."
أو "هذه بلدي"
Or, "That's my life."
أو "هذه حياتي"
All my life I've been told that the way we have to get ahead is to compete:
طول حياتي يقال لى ان الطريق المتاح لنا إلى المضي قدماً هو المنافسة:
get into the right school, get into the right job, get to the top,
الذهاب إلى المدرسة المناسبة، و الحصول على الوظيفة المناسبة، و الوصول للقمة،
and I've really never found it very inspiring.
و انا لم أجد حقاً ان هذا ملهماً جداً.
I've started and run businesses because invention is a joy,
لقد بدأت أدير أعمال لأن الأبتكار متعة،
and because working alongside brilliant, creative people
و لأن العمل مع ناس بارعين و مبتكرين
is its own reward.
فى حد ذاتها جائزة.
And I've never really felt very motivated by pecking orders or by superchickens
و انا لم أشعر قط بالتحفيز عبر الأوامر الهجومية أو بالدجاج السوبر
or by superstars.
أو باللامعين الأذكياء.
But for the past 50 years,
ولكن في الخمسين سنة الماضية،
we've run most organizations and some societies
كنا ندير معظم المؤسسات و بعض المجتمعات
along the superchicken model.
على نموذج الدجاج السوبر.
We've thought that success is achieved by picking the superstars,
كنا نحسب ان النجاح يأتي بإختيار اللامعين الأذكياء
the brightest men, or occasionally women, in the room,
أو ألمع الرجال او احياناً النساء في الغرفة
and giving them all the resources and all the power.
و إعطائهم كل الموارد و كل النفوذ.
And the result has been just the same as in William Muir's experiment:
و النتيجة كانت مثل النتيجة في تجربة ويلليم ميور:
aggression, dysfunction and waste.
عدوان و اختلال في الوظيفة و هدر.
If the only way the most productive can be successful
إذا كانت الطريقة الوحيدة لنجاح أقصى الإنتاج
is by suppressing the productivity of the rest,
هي قمع إنتاج الاخرين
then we badly need to find a better way to work
إذاً نحن حقاً نحتاج إلى وجود طريقة أفضل للعمل
and a richer way to live.
و طريقة ثرية أكثر للعيش.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So what is it that makes some groups
إذاً ما الذي يجعل بعض المجموعات بوضوح
obviously more successful and more productive than others?
أكثر نجاحاً و أكثر إنتاجاً عن الأخرين؟
Well, that's the question a team at MIT took to research.
حسناً، هذا هو السؤال الذي بحث عنه فريق من MIT.
They brought in hundreds of volunteers,
احضروا المئات من المتطوعين
they put them into groups, and they gave them very hard problems to solve.
و وضعوهم في مجموعات و اعطوا لهم مشاكل صعبة جداً لحلها.
And what happened was exactly what you'd expect,
و الذي حدث هو بالضبط الذي تتوقع حدوثه،
that some groups were very much more successful than others,
بعض المجموعات كانوا أكثر نجاحاً عن الأخرين
but what was really interesting was that the high-achieving groups
و لكن الشيء الذي كان ممتع حقاً هو أن مجموعات المتفوقين
were not those where they had one or two people
لم يكونوا المجموعات حيث يوجد شخص أو شخصين
with spectacularly high I.Q.
بنسبة ذكاء عالية و خارقة.
Nor were the most successful groups the ones that had the highest
و لا كانت المجموعات أكثر نجاحاً اولئك الذين كانت نسبة ذكائهم
aggregate I.Q.
الاجمالي الأعلى.
Instead, they had three characteristics, the really successful teams.
بدلا من ذلك، كان عند الفرق الناجحة حقاً ثلاث خصائص.
First of all, they showed high degrees of social sensitivity to each other.
أولًا، اظهروا درجة عالية من الحساسية الأجتماعية نحو بعضهم البعض.
This is measured by something called the Reading the Mind in the Eyes Test.
هذا يقاس بشيء يسمى "اختبار قراءة العقل في العيون".
It's broadly considered a test for empathy,
إنه بصورة عامة يُعتبر اختبار للتعاطف،
and the groups that scored highly on this
و المجموعات التي سجلت بشكل عالي فيه
did better.
قامت بالأفضل.
Secondly, the successful groups gave roughly equal time to each other,
ثانياً، المجموعات الناجحة أعطوا وقت متساوِ بحدية لبعضهم البعض.
so that no one voice dominated,
كي لا يهيمن صوت واحد،
but neither were there any passengers.
و لكن لم يوجد أي رُكٌاب.
And thirdly, the more successful groups
و ثالثاً، المجموعات الأكثر نجاحاً
had more women in them.
كان بينهم نساء أكثر.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Now, was this because women typically score more highly on
الآن، هل هذا كان بسبب ان النساء عادة يحرزون أعلى في
the Reading the Mind in the Eyes Test,
اختبار قراءة العقل في العيون،
so you're getting a doubling down on the empathy quotient?
بحيث تضاعف خصال التعاطف؟
Or was it because they brought a more diverse perspective?
او هل كانت بسبب انهم جاؤا بمنظور متنوع أكثر؟
We don't really know, but the striking thing about this experiment
نحن حقاً لا نعرف، و لكن الشيء المدهش في هذه التجربة
is that it showed what we know, which is some groups do better than others,
هي انها أظهرت ما نعرفه، أن بعض المجموعات يفعلون أفضل من الأخرين،
but what's key to that
و لكن المفتاح لهذا
is their social connectedness to each other.
هو الترابط الإجتماعي بين بعضهم البعض.
So how does this play out in the real world?
إذاً كيف هذا يمثل دوراً في الحياة الواقعية؟
Well, it means that what happens between people really counts,
حسناً، انها تعني ان ما يحدث بين الاشخاص يتخذ أهمية بالفعل
because in groups that are highly attuned and sensitive to each other,
لأن في المجموعات الواعية و الحساسة نحو بعضهم البعض بدرجة كبيرة،
ideas can flow and grow.
الافكار يمكنها التدفق و النمو.
People don't get stuck. They don't waste energy down dead ends.
الناس لا تتعطٌل. إنهم لا يهدرون الطاقة في طرق مسدودة.
An example: Arup is one of the world's most successful engineering firms,
مثال: اروب هي واحدة من أنجح الشركات الهندسية في العالم،
and it was commissioned to build the equestrian center
و كانت مُفوضة لبناء مركز للخيول
for the Beijing Olympics.
للألعاب الأولمبية في بكين.
Now, this building had to receive
الآن، كان يجب على هذا المبنى أن يستقبل
two and a half thousand really highly strung thoroughbred horses
ألفين و نصف ألف حصان من سلاسل أصيلة حقاً
that were coming off long-haul flights,
الذين كانوا ينتهوا من سفر مسافة طويلة،
highly jet-lagged, not feeling their finest.
و يعانوا من اضطراب الرحلات الجوية الطويلة، و لم يكونوا في احسن حالاتهم.
And the problem the engineer confronted was,
و المشكلة التي واجهت المهندس هي
what quantity of waste to cater for?
ما كمية النفايات المطلوبة ليقدموا الطعام؟
Now, you don't get taught this in engineering school -- (Laughter) --
الآن، هذا شيء لا تتعلمه في مدارس الهندسة (ضحك)
and it's not really the kind of thing you want to get wrong,
وهذا ليس حقاً شيء ترغب أن تُخطىء فيه،
so he could have spent months talking to vets, doing the research,
لذلك كان بإمكانه قضاء أشهر يتحدث مع اطباء بيطريين و القيام بالبحث
tweaking the spreadsheet.
و تعديل جدول البيانات.
Instead, he asked for help
لكن بدلاً عن ذلك، طَلَبَ المساعدة
and he found someone who had designed the Jockey Club in New York.
و وجد الشخص الذي صمم الجوكي كلوب في نيو يورك.
The problem was solved in less than a day.
تم حل المشكلة في اقل من يوم.
Arup believes that the culture of helpfulness
تعتقد شركة اروب أن ثقافة الرغبة في المساعدة
is central to their success.
هي مركز لنجاحهم.
Now, helpfulness sounds really anemic,
الآن، الرغبة في المساعدة تبدو ضعيفة حقاً
but it's absolutely core to successful teams,
و لكن قطعاً إنها الجوهر للفرق الناجحة
and it routinely outperforms individual intelligence.
و إنها بشكل روتيني تفوق إنجاز ذكاء شخص واحد.
Helpfulness means I don't have to know everything,
الرغبة في مساعدة الأخرين تعني لا يجب أن أعرف كل شيء،
I just have to work among people who are good at getting and giving help.
انا فقط يجب علٌي العمل مع أشخاص يجيدون أخذ و إعطاء المساعدة.
At SAP, they reckon that you can answer any question in 17 minutes.
في شركة ساب، إنهم يظنون أن بإمكانك الإجابة على أي سؤال في 17 دقيقة.
But there isn't a single high-tech company I've worked with
لكن لا يوجد شركة عالية التقنية واحدة من الذين عملت معهم
that imagines for a moment that this is a technology issue,
تتخيل للحظة أن هذه مشكلة تقنية،
because what drives helpfulness is people getting to know each other.
لأن الذي يحفٌز الرغبة في مساعدة الأخرين هو التعرف على بعضهم البعض.
Now that sounds so obvious, and we think it'll just happen normally,
الآن هذا يبدو واضحاً جداً، و نحن نظن انها طبيعياً ستحدث،
but it doesn't.
لكنها لا تحدث.
When I was running my first software company,
عندما كنت أدير اول شركة برمجيات لي
I realized that we were getting stuck.
أدركت اننا كنا نتعطٌل.
There was a lot of friction, but not much else,
كان يوجد العديد من النزاع، لكن هذا كان كل ما في الأمر،
and I gradually realized the brilliant, creative people that I'd hired
و تدريجياً لاحظت ان الاشخاص الأذكياء و المبدعين الذين عيٌنتهم
didn't know each other.
لم يعرفوا بعضهم البعض.
They were so focused on their own individual work,
كان كل تركيزهم على عملهم الفردي،
they didn't even know who they were sitting next to,
كانوا لا يعرفون حتى من هم جالسون بجوارهم،
and it was only when I insisted that we stop working
و كانت فقط عندما أصريت ان نتوقف العمل
and invest time in getting to know each other
و نستثمر الوقت في معرفة بعضنا البعض
that we achieved real momentum.
حققنا قوة دافعة حقيقية.
Now, that was 20 years ago, and now I visit companies
الآن، كان هذا منذ 20 سنة ماضية، و الآن أزور الشركات
that have banned coffee cups at desks
التي تمنع فناجين القهوة على المكاتب
because they want people to hang out around the coffee machines
لأنهم يريدون الناس أن يتسكعون عند آلات القهوة
and talk to each other.
و التحدث مع بعضهم البعض.
The Swedes even have a special term for this.
حتى أن السويديون عندهم مصطلح خاص من أجل ذلك.
They call it fika, which means more than a coffee break.
يسمونه "فيكا" مما تعني اكثر من إستراحة لتناول القهوة.
It means collective restoration.
إنها تعني ترميم جماعي.
At Idexx, a company up in Maine,
في أيدكس و هي شركة في ولاية مايين
they've created vegetable gardens on campus so that people
انشأوا حدائق نباتية في مبنى الشركة لكي يتسنى للناس
from different parts of the business
من أجزاء مختلفة في الأعمال
can work together and get to know the whole business that way.
العمل معاً و معرفة الأعمال كاملةً بهذه الطريقة.
Have they all gone mad?
هل فقدوا عقلهم جميعاً؟
Quite the opposite -- they've figured out that when the going gets tough,
بالعكس تماماً - إنهم فهموا أن عندما تشتد الأمور،
and it always will get tough
و هي دائماً ستشتد
if you're doing breakthrough work that really matters,
إذا كان عملك يحقق تقدماً مهماً حقاً،
what people need is social support,
ما يحتاجه الناس هو دعم إجتماعي،
and they need to know who to ask for help.
و يحتاجون ان يعرفوا لمن يلجئون لطلب المساعدة.
Companies don't have ideas; only people do.
الشركات لا تملك افكار بل الناس هم من يمتلكونهم.
And what motivates people
و الذي يحفز الناس
are the bonds and loyalty and trust they develop between each other.
هو الارتباط و الولاء و الثقة التي يطورونها بين بعضهم البعض.
What matters is the mortar,
ما يهم هو مواد البناء
not just the bricks.
ليس الطوب فقط.
Now, when you put all of this together,
الآن، عندما تضع كل هذا معاً،
what you get is something called social capital.
ما ينتج عن ذلك شيء يسمى رأس المال الإجتماعي.
Social capital is the reliance and interdependency that builds trust.
رأس المال الإجتماعي هو الاعتماد و الترابط الذي يبني الثقة.
The term comes from sociologists who were studying communities
جاء المصطلح من علماء الإجتماع الذين كانوا يدرسون المجتمعات
that proved particularly resilient in times of stress.
التي أثبتت مرونة خاصة في أوقات الضغط.
Social capital is what gives companies momentum,
رأس المال الإجتماعي هو ما يعطي الشركات قوة دافعة،
and social capital is what makes companies robust.
و رأس المال الإجتماعي هو ما يجعل الشركات متينة.
What does this mean in practical terms?
ماذا يعني هذا من الناحية العملية؟
It means that time is everything,
هذا يعني ان الوقت هو كل شيء،
because social capital compounds with time.
لأن رأس المال الإجتماعي مُركٌب مع الوقت.
So teams that work together longer get better, because it takes time
إذاً الفرق التي تعمل معاً لوقت أطول تتحسن، لأنها تأخذ وقت
to develop the trust you need for real candor and openness.
لتطوير الثقة التي تحتاجها للصراحة و الانفتاح الحقيقي.
And time is what builds value.
وإنه الوقت الذي يبني قيمة.
When Alex Pentland suggested to one company
عندما أقترح اليكس بينتلاند لأحدى الشركات
that they synchronize coffee breaks
أن يزامنوا وقت إستراحة تناول القهوة
so that people would have time to talk to each other,
كي يكون للناس وقت للحديث مع بعضهم البعض،
profits went up 15 million dollars,
زادت الأرباح بنسبة 15 مليون دولار،
and employee satisfaction went up 10 percent.
و زاد رضا الموظفين بنسبة 10 فى المئة.
Not a bad return on social capital,
ليست عائد سيئ لرأس المال الأجتماعي،
which compounds even as you spend it.
التي تتركٌب حتى عندما تنفقها.
Now, this isn't about chumminess, and it's no charter for slackers,
الآن، هذا ليس عن الود، و ليست صفقة للكسالى
because people who work this way tend to be kind of scratchy,
لأن الناس التي تعمل بهذه الطريقة تميل إلى ان تكون عنيدة نوعاً ما
impatient, absolutely determined to think for themselves
و غير صبورة و مصٌرة كلياً للتفكير بأنفسهم
because that's what their contribution is.
لأن هذا هو إسهامهم.
Conflict is frequent because candor is safe.
الخلاف متكرر لأن الشخص الصريح آمن.
And that's how good ideas turn into great ideas,
و هذا كيف تتحول الأفكار الجيدة لأفكار رائعة،
because no idea is born fully formed.
لأنه لا توجد فكرة تولد كامله.
It emerges a little bit as a child is born,
إنها تنبثق قليلاً مثل طفل مولود،
kind of messy and confused, but full of possibilities.
نوعا ما فوضوي و مضطرب لكن مليء بالإحتمالات.
And it's only through the generous contribution, faith and challenge
و عبر الإسهام الوافر و الإيمان و التحدي
that they achieve their potential.
يحققون إمكاناتهم.
And that's what social capital supports.
و هذا ما يدعمه رأس المال الإجتماعي.
Now, we aren't really used to talking about this,
الآن، نحن عادةً لا نتحدث عن هذا بالفعل،
about talent, about creativity, in this way.
و عن الموهبة و عن الإبتكار بهذه الطريقة.
We're used to talking about stars.
نحن عادة نتحدث عن النجوم.
So I started to wonder, well, if we start working this way,
هكذا بدأت اتساءل، إذا بدأنا العمل بهذه الطريقة،
does that mean no more stars?
هل هذا يعني عدم وجود المزيد من النجوم؟
So I went and I sat in on the auditions
لذا ذهبت و حضرت إختبارات الاداء
at the Royal Academy of Dramatic Art in London.
في الأكاديمية الملكية للفنون المسرحية في لندن.
And what I saw there really surprised me,
و ما رأيته هناك اذهلني حقاً،
because the teachers weren't looking for individual pyrotechnics.
لأن المدرسين لم يكونوا يبحثوا عن الشخص صاحب الأداء العظيم.
They were looking for what happened between the students,
إنهم كانوا يبحثون عن ما حدث بين الطلاب،
because that's where the drama is.
لأن هذا هو مكان الدراما.
And when I talked to producers of hit albums,
و عندما تحدثت مع منتجين ألبومات ناجحة،
they said, "Oh sure, we have lots of superstars in music.
قالوا "بالتأكيد، نحن لدينا العديد من النجوم في الموسيقى.
It's just, they don't last very long.
المشكلة فقط، أنهم لا يستمرون طويلاً.
It's the outstanding collaborators who enjoy the long careers,
المتعاونون البارزون هم من يستمتعون بالوظائف الطويلة،
because bringing out the best in others is how they found the best
لأن إظهار الأفضل في الآخرين هي الطريقة لإكتشاف الأفضل
in themselves."
في أنفسهم."
And when I went to visit companies that are renowned
و عندما زرت الشركات المعروفة
for their ingenuity and creativity,
ببراعتها و إبتكارها،
I couldn't even see any superstars,
لم أرى أي نجوم،
because everybody there really mattered.
لأن كلهم هناك كانوا مهمين لهم.
And when I reflected on my own career,
و عندما فكرت في مهنتي،
and the extraordinary people I've had the privilege to work with,
و الأشخاص الرائعون الذين كان لي الشرف للعمل معهم،
I realized how much more we could give each other
أدركت كيف يمكننا ان نعطي بعضنا البعض أكثر
if we just stopped trying to be superchickens.
إذا توقفنا عن المحاولة لنبقى دجاج سوبر.
(Laughter) (Applause)
(ضحك)(تصفيق)
Once you appreciate truly how social work is,
بمجرد ان نقدٌر حقاً كيفية العمل الإجتماعي
a lot of things have to change.
الكثير من الأمور يجب أن تتغير.
Management by talent contest has routinely pitted
مسابقة الإدارة بالموهبة وضعت بشكل روتيني
employees against each other.
الموظفين ليعملوا ضد بعضهم البعض.
Now, rivalry has to be replaced by social capital.
الآن، لابد من استبدال المنافسة برأس المال الإجتماعي.
For decades, we've tried to motivate people with money,
لعقود، حاولنا تحفيز الناس بالمال،
even though we've got a vast amount of research that shows
رغم اننا نملك عدد هائل من البحوث التي أظهرت
that money erodes social connectedness.
ان المال يحطّم الترابط الإجتماعي.
Now, we need to let people motivate each other.
الآن، نحن نحتاج ان نترك الناس يحفزون بعضهم البعض.
And for years, we've thought that leaders were heroic soloists who were expected,
و لسنين عدة، نظن ان القادة هم أبطال منفردين الذين كان من المتوقع منهم
all by themselves, to solve complex problems.
حل المشكلات المعقدة كلها بأنفسهم.
Now, we need to redefine leadership
الآن، نحن نحتاج إلى إعادة تعريف القيادة
as an activity in which conditions are created
بإعتبارها النشاط الذي يتم فيها تهيئة الظروف
in which everyone can do their most courageous thinking together.
حيث يمكن للجميع القيام بالتفكير الجريء معاً.
We know that this works.
نحن نعلم ان هذا سيجدي نفعاً.
When the Montreal Protocol called for the phasing out of CFCs,
عندما طلب برتوكول مونتريال سحب كلوروفلوروكربون تدريجياً،
the chlorofluorocarbons implicated in the hole in the ozone layer,
لأن الكلوروفلوروكربون مُقْحَم في الثقب في طبقة الأوزون،
the risks were immense.
كانت المخاطر هائلة.
CFCs were everywhere,
كان الكلوروفلوروكربون في كل مكان،
But one team that rose to the challenge adopted three key principles.
لكن فريق واحد من الذين قبلوا التحدي اعتمدوا على ثلاثة مبادئ رئيسية.
The first was the head of engineering, Frank Maslen, said,
الأول كان رئيس الهندسة فرانك ماسلن قال
there will be no stars in this team.
لن يوجد نجوم في هذا الفريق.
We need everybody.
نحن نحتاج إلى الجميع.
Everybody has a valid perspective.
كل شخص يملك منظورا صالحا.
Second, we work to one standard only:
الثاني، نحن نقوم بالعمل على معيار واحد فقط:
the best imaginable.
أفضل ما يمكن تصوره.
And third, he told his boss, Geoff Tudhope,
و الثالث، قال لرئيسه جيف تدهوب
that he had to butt out,
انه إضطر إلى الخروج،
because he knew how disruptive power can be.
لأنه كان يعرف كيف يمكن للقوة أن تكون مدمرة.
Now, this didn't mean Tudhope did nothing.
الآن، هذا لا يعني ان تدهوب لم يفعل شيئاً.
He gave the team air cover,
أعطى للفريق غطاء جوي،
and he listened to ensure that they honored their principles.
و كان يستمع ليضمن انهم حافظوا على مبادئهم.
And it worked: Ahead of all the other companies tackling this hard problem,
و بالفعل هذا ما حدث: قبل كل الشركات الأخرى التي حاولت معالجة هذه المشكلة الصعبة،
this group cracked it first.
كانت هذه هي المجموعة الاولى التي تقضي على المشكلة.
And to date, the Montreal Protocol
و حتى الآن، برتوكول مونتريال
is the most successful international environmental agreement
هي أنجح اتفاقية بيئية دولية
ever implemented.
نفذت من أي وقت مضى.
There was a lot at stake then,
كان هناك الكثير على حافة الخطر،
and there's a lot at stake now,
و يوجد الآن الكثير على حافة الخطر الآن،
and we won't solve our problems if we expect it to be solved
ونحن لن نحل مشاكلنا إذا كنا نتوقع أن يتم حلها
by a few supermen or superwomen.
من قبل بضعة رجال سوبر أو نساء سوبر.
Now we need everybody,
نحن نحتاج الآن للجميع،
because it is only when we accept that everybody has value
لأنه بمجرد ان نتقبل أن الجميع لديه قيمة
that we will liberate the energy and imagination and momentum we need
سوف نحرر الطاقة والخيال والقوة الدافعة التي نحتاجها
to create the best beyond measure.
لإنشاء أفضل ما خارج المقياس.
Thank you.
شكراً.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)